All right. So, okay, thank you, Animesh,
for your time. First of all,
let me just speak a bit about what we are
planning to do.
So me and DR recognised a problem around
the way we consume news. And, you know,
Mhm.
we wanted to come up with an idea.
where, you know,
it's much more convenient for people to
read, consume what they want.
And one place we felt like, you know,
what's happening these days, right?
We feel that, you know,
media is very one-sided or, you know,
it's either bought or we don't get
Yeah.
different perspectives.
right? For example,
the way one example Diya was giving was
Mm.
that, you know,
the way say a political leader,
an important political leader is getting
spoken about in our country versus say
Hmm.
some other country,
it could be very different, right?
Right.
So it's all about perspectives. So
Hmm.
So we just wanted to understand, you know,
so there'll be some questions around this
piece, news consumption,
and how do you sort of get different
perspectives?
Are you even looking for different
Mhm.
perspectives? So some of these things.
So I have a set of questions.
I will go through that.
We also have like a very early prototype
that I can show you and you can tell me
what you feel about it or do you think.
There needs to be a little more to it,
or that's good, et cetera. OK.
Mm.
Right, yeah.
So let me start with the first question,
which is...
Mm.
So how do you typically stay informed
about current events? You know,
what is your daily routine like?
Okay,
so because we live in the era of reels,
I guess I have a lot of channels that I
trust, honestly, like first post, new,
Mmh.
like these independent news media is what
I have started to trust because I guess...
Okay.
that they are bringing the best and most
pure form of unbiased news that we are
Mm.
expecting these days.
Because if you would have caught up with
the narratives that were floating around
recently,
the protest and all that happened,
it was completely like polarised.
Yeah.
with our mainstream media versus this.
And I don't think like mainstream media,
Thank you.
like my parents did not even know what
exactly was going on.
Okay.
And I had a very different picture of
what's going on because now we have so
Beautiful.
many, you know,
influencers making actual content right
there.
Or we have these independent news medias
who are not really afraid of, you know,
speaking about the truth that's out there,
not. So I really like that.
Yes.
So I am that kind of person.
I'll actually see what's there in Ajtak
as well, but also what's there in online.
And I like to take my own call and like
my own decision without any bias.
So my news consumption.
It primarily, as a when I was growing up,
had was like newspaper and a very
traditional form of news. Now,
it's like more,
Bing.
it's like quick bites that you get on
Instagram or YouTube, right?
If I want to deep dive into a particular
topic, I like to go search and...
Hmm.
read up a little bit more on that
specific news post from different media
And.
houses. And yeah,
that makes me because I think I have I
definitely have trust issues with our
media, right?
So I won't follow this one person and be
like, okay,
this is the this is the truth and this is
what I can form my opinions on.
So I like to collect a lot of data.
and then try to make an informed choice.
That's so it's very online and very mixed
OPS.
media kind of an approach from my side.
Okay. Okay. All right. Thank you. Okay.
Have you ever read about the same story
from two different sources and noticed
they are told very differently?
Can you walk me through that experience?
Like what did it feel like for you?
Yes.
So have you first of all experienced this?
Two, what did it feel like?
Mm.
I mean,
this latest event brought out this
discrepancy. By the latest event,
I mean the protest that just happened,
Yeah, I mean, yeah, in the studio.
right?
So that has brought out the most
discrepancy that you can see,
like the debates that are happening on
news channel are off topic.
like people are just discussing random
things.
The news that is floating around is like,
you know, oh,
the protesters have started throwing
stones or all of this, all of this.
But when you see actually accounts of the
people who are actually there getting
We do.
beaten up by police personals and all of
that. So there's a like very different.
side of story and it does actually messes
up with your perception of what's going
on out there because you are not out
there and news is the only way you get to
know what's happening.
And when like these credible,
I'm quoting in air right now,
these credible news sources are.
not really doing their job because they
are under some influence.
And we will see like a lot of these
independent people making more relatable
content and which like really relates to
you.
You can clearly make out like what's
happening.
And the distinction was also quite clear.
So, yeah,
it doesn't feel nice to like just,
you know,
be convinced because of someone else's
narrative,
but I feel like not a good feeling to be
honest, but you,
as a person who's consuming the news.
Mm.
you need to really have that informed,
have that mindset to question what's
being told to you. If that doesn't happen,
then you know,
Team.
you can just become a one-sided news
reader and also you will be like,
you know,
just following someone else's narrative.
It.
Okay,
and do you spend a lot of time
So, then happened.
cross-referencing news? Do you do that?
For example, say you,
there is one side of things that you see
from first post,
Mhm.
Date.
then do you also go to Al Jazeera and
have a look at it or say BBC? Yeah.
Yeah.
Right.
So these global news channels actually do
a much better job of reporting, I feel.
I definitely cheque.
Al Jazeera is on top of my list.
What's that news channel? Vyond News,
Fox News. So they never sell you a...
Mm.
narrative, they say,
they tell you what's actually happening
and you can,
that's the kind of news I like where I am
Mm.
not being told to form an opinion.
I'm being told facts and the opinions are
for me to form.
And you can only do that when you have
Got it.
like multiple cross references from.
You know, multiple credible sources, yeah,
unlike we have in our country.
Mm.
Okay.
Okay,
I'm just going through the questions.
I mean, with your answers,
you're answering quite a lot, so...
Mhm.
So quickly checking.
So imagine there is a tool that is
showing you all, okay, before that,
you know, have you used news aggregators,
tools like Google News or Feedly?
I don't know what it is,
but like there are generally a lot of
these news aggregator, for example,
Google News probably is one of the most
common ways of consuming news.
Hey.
So do you do you think that's one place
to you go quite a lot to?
I remember before, a couple of years ago,
there used to be an app which was quite
nice. It will,
it's like a scroll behaviour itself and
they will shorten the news.
I completely missing the name of the app.
I think I, I know, I know. Yeah, I...
It was that.
Yeah, I think it became in shorts,
in shorts.
We could call it.
In short, yeah, yeah, in short,
I used to really like that format,
In shorts, yeah.
like you had the ability to know what's
going on and, like, in a quick glance,
you can understand what's happening,
and even if you want to dive deep,
you can,
so I that was a very good approach.
Google News also, I have.
Checked out it, but I,
I'm I it's difficult to understand where
all of this is coming from. Like,
I don't have my like the sources that I
really trust coming there,
so I don't understand what's the
algorithm behind aggregating that news is,
so that visibility I don't think we all
have.
So I guess whatever is trending comes to
Google News and whatever is happening
Yeah.
across the world or whatever is picked up
by like the media houses,
Mm.
that sort of gets aggregated.
So I don't often go there directly and
just cheque for news,
but whenever I do feel about...
certain topic that I want to learn,
I go and I cheque it out and I'll see
like a lot of related news post about
that topic or that person or whatever
event that is happening. Yeah.
Okay, fine.
I want to use some news apps.
I think Hindustan Times,
I got a free subscription,
so I'd used it for three months.
That was also quite good. But yeah,
it's a bit costly to maintain.
Yeah, yeah, all great, fine. Let me,
is there anything else that you want to
I like 3 new sources.
Yeah.
add, Animesh?
Do you have like a wish list of what
consumption of news or information needs
to be like?
Mm.
So because there are so now the other
problem is that because there are so many
now individual houses and people who are
doing all of this,
you get too many perspectives also.
So that's also a bit confusing.
Mm.
Who do you trust? Who do you not trust?
And so, I, I wish, like...
I'll get like some kind of like a rating,
frustrating like we have for movies,
Yes.
right? You have IBM,
which is rated by people,
Yeah.
but you also have Rotten Tomatoes,
which is rated by critics.
Yeah.
Mhm.
So I'd really like somebody who's like a
news critic.
Hmm.
critique, critique, sorry, news critic,
critiquing the news and maybe some sort
of algorithm which tells us like how
credible this is.
That would be a game changer.
All right.
So one thing you mentioned is that,
you know,
you really like the short form of short
forms of news so that you can read and
Yeah.
then you can decide what you want to.
Are there also specific subjects that you
are, I know when I say news immediately,
you know, we think of political news,
Yeah.
Mhm.
but do you also think that the news
should also be?
based on your interest or do you think
one should experience news in like a news,
right?
Like you should know what's going on in
every kind of aspect of things,
whether it's politics, science,
Right.
or do you like to consume news that you
are interested in? What's your...
perspective on that.
Okay,
so I think if it's a major event that's
happening,
I would like to know without being it in
a particular category of interest.
But sometimes, you know,
there's so much happening,
like who's winning in IPL,
Mm.
what's happening in like some hockey
Premier League.
All of that is like sometimes very
irrelevant and just for me, I am,
I don't really follow lots of sport,
but I like to know what's happening in
tech, what's happening in AI,
what's happening in like politics,
what's happening in, you know,
maybe the travel industry or what's
Mmh.
happening with education.
So these topics are more of my interest,
but I would also like to know who's
Thank you.
winning the World Cup, right?
Who's winning the some major level,
Mm.
who's winning Olympics is something that
I would like to track,
but not every match of an IPL or every
match of a test series. So it's like a...
I definitely there has to be some
priority given to like what kind of news
content in which area you would like to
consume.
It'll be nice to also know major event.
I that's just my way of consume.
Mhm.
I that because it's also a lot of things
that are happening right?
There's so many people in this.
Yeah, yeah, true.
And everything we cannot consume,
so we have to also look out for our own
sanity. So yeah, that's.
Okay.
And why do you consume news?
Is it just for information?
Is it for infotainment or is it for
education?
Any specific reason why you can consume
news?
And.
Yeah, I mean,
it's good to always know what's going on.
I mean,
you shouldn't be living under a rock,
I feel, because we have, as humans,
moral responsibility to also know what's
Love you.
happening to other people, right?
Our lives are there, but...
Mmh.
other people's lives also matter.
So that way I definitely like to know
what's going on and if I could contribute
or if there is a way that, you know,
Mhm.
I could make a difference,
I would also seek out for those
Hmm.
opportunities, but rarely that can happen.
Okay.
Yeah.
Okay, great.
So now I'm just going to share something
very quickly we created, okay?
And give a very honest, you know,
opinion about what do you think.
It's really like the first hand.
Imagine giving a problem to Bob and it
just created something.
You can share your screen to.
Tell me how, how it.
Write one second.
I mean,
I think UI is not very difficult to
understand. That's pretty straightforward.
But like, what do you think?
Okay.
Is there something to whatever we spoke
about? Does it match or no, Namita?
This is like, what? So yeah.
Mhm.
You can share, see my screen name.
Yeah, I can, I can see the screen, yeah.
So you have all topics,
you've got topics here.
What's perspective return?
I like to know the info about this link.
Take care.
So, one thing that...
Okay, you have these days, right? Yeah,
right. Okay, okay.
I wanted to know when was this news?
available and so how
So for example, on an ongoing topic,
right,
do you have like a thread that is
maintained about the news? For example,
Mm.
the protest happened for 30 days, right?
And I see one card and there are like a
Mm.
lot of events that keep on happening.
It's not like a one-time thing.
Hey.
There's like back and forth,
like the oil trade that's happening.
Yeah.
It's been going on for so long.
So I think that would also be a nice
thing when you would know based on
Oh.
Yeah.
timeline what's happening from the
inception till the current wherever it is,
Hmm.
even if it's like all settled now,
we should still be able to like maybe
Mm.
that could be a nice thing.
This looks nice.
It gives me the what the heading is.
Mm.
I guess if I click it, yeah, it'll open.
Where is it sourcing the news from?
That is also listed. 16.
Original articles, I think, on the right.
Mm.
Thirteen, yeah, you have that.
That's good. Quite like it.
So this takes me to the deep dive section
in believing it.
Mm.
Okay,
so I can follow some topics and these are
all the topics and you have segregated it.
Does radar deep dives? Okay,
Hey.
the same thing.
OK.
Mm.
Yeah,
but which is the primary navigation I'm
looking.
I don't know.
This is actually created by Diya,
Confused.
but I think we just wanted to sort of
understand.
No.
But can you just think about like,
imagine there is an experience where you
In.
can kind of, it's a lot more,
what is a personalised experience going
to?
Is that something you would like or do
you want news to be known?
I don't want a personalised experience.
Or what should it be? Yeah.
I would like to experience. Definitely,
I like to have some personality,
but like this topic,
like today's topic and all topics,
I would like to see what's happening with
regards to what I have chosen as my
Mm.
primary topics,
but also something that's not in my topic
Wu.
but actually is gaining too much traction
or.
You know,
it's going on like a major thing in the
world that I'd like to definitely. Also,
maybe like something that's biggest that
Mm.
is going on that could be surfaced here.
I don't see any.
Mm.
Videos that I could maybe cheque out.
Okay.
Great videos, maybe some links to that and
It's looking very plain.
Maybe some images will be nice.
Okay.
Get the depth of what's happening.
Yeah, absolutely.
I think in news that's very important.
Because there's too much to read and
again, like even if I see this,
this is disputed,
this is happening in India,
blah blah blah.
So you can only read this much and some
Right.
topics. So I would like to...
At least read three more lines, I guess,
here.
So at least I don't have to open each
card.
Okay.
Because to even finish this,
I'll have to actually go inside and read
the whole thing.
So maybe like a...
overall summary which is giving me enough
overview so that I can choose to go and
deep dive.
Mhm.
I do see this and like a...
Right,
and also nowadays we have so much of...
short media content so people's like
attention span is going for a toss.
So you've got like 2 minutes to...
Mm.
Read something or know about something.
So then maybe you can also have that here
Wu.
like some
shorts,
even Al Jazeera is making like a deal for
like 1 1/2 minutes or something these
days.
All of these people have started to do
these bite-sized information,
so maybe that could also be associated
with these.
Okay, fine.
Because those are public channels,
I feel you can definitely take it out
from YouTube and it's still.
Hmm.
Okay.
Apart from that, this looks good,
just like maybe some pictures would be
appreciated.
Mm.
Where can I choose my topics from?
That is here.
You can I think right now only following
you can follow kind of thing.
Yeah, I will follow that.
Explain topics.
Do you consume your news a lot on your
phone or is is do you use a desktop to
desktop or television to consume the news?
What's your meeting?
Currently, I don't own a television,
so it gets difficult.
Yeah.
Mostly it's either on my phone,
because I usually do it on free time.
Otherwise,
if there's like a bigger topic that is
Okay, bye.
going on, I use laptop and see YouTube.
I mean, I don't screen size is not a big.
Problem.
Okay, but phone I feel right,
like I think most of us these days,
Like, open his post.
like we sit with a cup of tea and then we
want to,
Right.
we don't sit specifically for news,
you know, the way our parents would sit,
Diya, every morning.
that's not the case.
We generally like whenever we have our
Okay.
free time and.
That's the that's the kind of behaviour
that we are going into, right? Yeah.
Yeah, actually, that's the biggest.
Wu.
Right,
biggest shift is like when we go home and
you see, okay,
your parents are actually starting TV at
Yeah, yeah, same here, same here.
8. My dad is not going through that,
that yeah, both they will cut, cut,
cut 10 minutes,
60 minutes and they'll cover 100 news
topics there, that time.
Oh,
that is something that's a big favourite
Yeah, they will.
for my mother also, like, so that, yeah,
talk about short bites.
Exactly,
exactly that start minutes like that, so..
.
It's like one news broken down by 5
topics back-to-back.
They will say 5 statements,
one news is gone, then some other thing.
Okay.
And then they will have.
So I actually really like that format
also.
Very quickly you can get a lot of things.
But now I've seen also my dad looking at
like Al Jazeera on TV.
Right, he's, yeah, that that's a channel,
and he's like, yeah, they're good news,
Ohh, OK.
because they cover a lot more like
Palestine, Israel,
Different have all news, uh,
Middle East with, I think, uh,
and he's too much into news,
so we like that.
is the thing, yeah.
Yeah,
I like the fact that sources are
Team.
mentioned, perspectives are there,
but can I choose my own sources,
some preferred sources at least?
I think you can just deep dive, deep dive,
not deep dive,
maybe just click on anything.
I think you can.
No, you can't.
Oh, this is where I follow this topic. OK.
Yeah,
I don't think you can follow the topic
here,
but I don't think we have given an option
of.
choosing a thing.
Mhm.
But then the problem with that would be
we will end up choosing news channels
that we agree with. Either we sort of,
sort of, you know, like these are,
Right, right.
I don't know,
but we should think about it that because
Mm.
maybe I don't want to see everything.
Yeah.
Yeah, it was the.
Problematic sometimes, and even in the TV.
So yeah, I would rather,
even if it's coming from multiple sources,
I would like to place low weightages on
some channels because of my past
Hey.
experiences. Okay,
now the trust is broken,
Ohh.
you can't keep coming back and saying
things, it's gone. So yeah.
Good. This looks quite nice.
You guys are done with your thing.
Oh my God, we have.
No, no, no, there is just so much more,
and now after talking to you,
I have been getting a lot of ideas as
well, so...
What is the Save button?
Ohh, following the lot more,
lot of repetitions up, go even refinement,
I think he gave navigation, I think.
All right, OK. Thank you, Animesh.
I think we can have, yeah.
If you have any more perspective,
let me know. Meanwhile,
this was very helpful.
I am glad I also spoke to someone who has.
Nice.
Mmh.
good, who follows, who sees news a lot.
I think the best people would actually be
our parents. But yeah,
their way of consuming news is very,
Yeah, they are.
so my father, for example,
I think I can stop recording now.
Hmm.
Stop recording.